The four years Fushi spent devoting himself
to what could be considered his family
（観察者）日々を家族に
ささげるように暮らした４年間が
caused him to grow like a human being.
フシを人間のように成長させた
Invited by their friend Rean,
友人のリーンに招待され
Fushi joins Gugu in attending
her birthday party.
フシはグーグーと共に
誕生日パーティーに出席する
I...
（リーン）私ね…
キャッ
However...
（観察者）だが…
♪～
～♪
They're here.
It's the Nokkers.
（観察者）来たぞ ノッカーだ
（フシ）あ…
Its core is beneath the ground here.
（観察者）ヤツの核は この下だ
It has spread its roots
throughout this entire region.
ここ一帯に根を張り巡らしている
It'll soon destroy this place.
まもなく ここを破壊するだろう
（招待客たちの悲鳴）
What was that?
（男性）何なんだ！
I'm scared!
（男の子）怖いよ！
Everyone, get outside! Run!
みんな外へ！　逃げて！
Take Meer.
（フシ）ミールを
（男性）ああ？
You get away!
おう お前も逃げろ！
うわっ…
（フシの吠(ほ)え声）
Now, while you still can!
サア 今のうちに…
（悲鳴）
Awakening
（人々の悲鳴）
Gugu!
グーグー！
（グーグー）ぐ…
Somebody!
（リーン）誰か… 誰か助けて！
Somebody help!
What the hell is this?
（グーグー）何だよ これ…
ベタベタしてやがる
It's so sticky.
うわっ！　生き物か？
Is it alive?!
ん？
Grab this!
ぐっ
（リーンの婚約者）
これに つかまれ！
（グーグー）うう…
ぐぐぐ… ぐっ
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Are you all right?
（婚約者）大丈夫かい？
Yeah.
（グーグー）ああ ありがとう
Thanks.
I only have some scrapes.
かすり傷だけだ 助かったよ
You're a savior.
Thank goodness, Gugu.
よかった グーグー
What the heck happened?
（グーグー）
一体 何が起きたんだ？
I don't know.
（婚約者）
さあ… 急に屋敷が崩れ始めた
The mansion just started collapsing.
It couldn't be...
（グーグー）ハッ まさか…
Gugu!
（リーン）グーグー！
（グーグー）
ハァハァハァ… フシ？
Fushi!
Gugu, I'm sorry.
グーグー ごめんなさい
It's my fault that it's here.
オレのセイで あれがキタ
I knew it.
（グーグー）やっぱり
Everyone has run away.
ミンナ 逃げた
Only those two are left.
アトは その２人だけ
Get a grip!
（リーンの父）
おい しっかりしろ！
But they're both hurt.
（フシ）でも２人とも イタイ…
（父）おい！
Hurry.
（フシ）でも２人とも イタイ…
早ク… 早クしないと
There's no time.
Shit! It's collapsing!
ヤバい 崩れるぞ！
（人々の悲鳴）
（グーグーの荒い息）
Dad! Mom!
パパ！　ママ！
（侍女）よかった 無事で…
Wait.
（リーン）待って！
グーグー 行かないで
Gugu... Don't go.
You have to know that I...
わ… 私…
あなたのこと…
あっ
（グーグーの荒い息）
Fushi!
（グーグー）フシ！
Where are you?
どこだ！
（瓦礫(がれき)が崩れる音）
（フシ）うっ ハァハァハァ…
Fushi!
（グーグー）ああ フシ！
Damn it!
なんてこった
昔みてえになっちまって…
You look like you used to.
Thanks.
ありがとう
Where's the enemy?
（グーグー）敵はどこだ？
ぶっ倒してやる
I'll kill it.
I haven't seen it yet.
まだ見てない 隠れてる
It's hiding.
（物音）
（ノッカーの吠え声）
There it is.
（グーグー）出たな よけろ！
Move!
（２人）うっ
It can't grow its arms out like before.
（グーグー）こいつ 前みたいに
腕が伸びねえのか
Good thing, too.
助かるぜ
Take this!
くらえ はあっ！
Gugu...
グーグー
It's not the same as the last one.
これ 前のと違う
（グーグー）ああ… 炎が効かねえ
The fire isn't working.
It's the stone armor.
石の鎧(よろい)か
（ノッカーのうなり声）
（２人）うわっ
What is happening?!
（グーグー）
く… どうなってんだ！
Grab on, Gugu!
つかまって グーグー！
It's the squiggly things again.
（グーグー）またウニョウニョ！
まさか こいつが動かしてるのか？
Is that thing controlling them?
They're closing in.
迫ってくる！　挟み込む気だ
It's trying to crush us!
Fushi, you go first!
フシ 先に行け！
Okay!
（フシ）うん！
ふっ
んん…
うっ…
What do we do, Gugu?
どうしよう グーグー…
I don't know how to beat it.
オレ… 勝ち方が分からない
That thing has something inside it.
（グーグー）あいつには中身がある
そうだったよな？
Isn't that right?
Yeah.
（フシ）うん
Which means...
（グーグー）だとすると
あれの表面は石だ
Its surface is made of stone,
but it's not an intricate
sculpture or anything.
だが精密な彫刻なんかじゃねえ
It's just a bunch of rocks mashed together.
ただの石の寄せ集め
And inside, it's just flesh.
中身は ただの肉
Let's get on top of him
and find a weak spot!
あいつに登って すき間を探すぞ！
Got it.
（フシ）わかった
（フシ）く… う… く…
（グーグー）んん… くっ
It's pretty thick inside.
結構 奥まで詰まってやがるな
Fushi! Give me a stick!
フシ 棒をくれ！
I'll pry it open.
こじ開けてやる
I need more! Give me another one!
まだだ！　もっとくれ
（ノッカーのうめき声）
あ！
There it is! Its insides!
あった 中身だ！
It's nice and soft. I bet it'll burn nicely.
軟らかくて よく燃えそうだ！
はあっ！
Yes!
（グーグー）やった！
（２人）あ…
（グーグー）ハッ あれをやれ！
Get that!
（フシ）えいっ
あ…
（グーグー）おお… ぐあっ
あっ
（グーグー）イテテ…
Are you all right, Fushi?
大丈夫か フシ？
Yeah.
（フシ）うん…
But that was our chance,
and I let it get away.
でもチャンスだったのに
逃げられた
That's just how strong we are.
（グーグー）
それだけ 俺らが強いってことだ
We did it, Fushi.
やったな フシ！
Thanks, Gugu.
ありがとう グーグー
I would have lost without you.
グーグーがいなかったら
また負けてた
I'm pretty weak for someone who's immortal.
オレ フジミのくせに
弱いから…
I've always got your back
when you need help.
（グーグー）困ったことがあったら
いくらでも助ける
That's what it means to be brothers.
それが兄弟ってもんだぜ
（グーグー）フ…
フ… フシ！　フシ！
Fushi!
Yay! Just in time!
やった 間に合った！
Rean?!
（グーグー）リーン？
い… いつから いた？
Wh-When did you get here?
You can't be here!
ダメじゃないか 来ちゃ！
There's a lot I want to ask you, too.
私も聞きたいことは
たくさんあるわ
But we need to get out of here first.
でも まずは
ここから出ましょう
Come on. This way.
さあ こっち！
Fushi...
（グーグー）フシ…
（衝撃音）
キャッ
It's collapsing!
崩れてくる
Run!
（グーグー）走ろう！
（２人の荒い息）
（人々）ああ…
What's that dust cloud?
（酒爺(さけじい)）何だ あの土煙は？
I have a bad feeling about this.
胸がザワザワするぞ
（鼓動）
（フシ）ハァ…
んん… うっ
フゥ
（鼓動）
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Gugu...
グーグー…
ん？　ハッ
うっ ぐ… うう…
（鼓動）
This isn't my pain.
これは…
オレの痛みじゃない
Hey, what is that?
（人々の悲鳴）
（男性）おい 何だ あれ？
This is bad.
（人々の悲鳴）
（男性）ヤバいぞ！
Where's our daughter?
ねえ あの子は？
Rean...
リーン？
Rean!
リーン！
A-Are you all right, Rean?
（グーグー）
だ… 大丈夫かい リーン？
Yeah.
うん
う…
ぐわっ
I have to hurry.
早く… しないと…
（衝撃音）
It's pretty noisy outside.
（グーグー）外が騒がしいな
I-Isn't it heavy?
お… 重たいでしょ？
Nah. It's not that bad.
（グーグー）いや そうでもないよ
Relax.
安心して… すぐ助けが…
Help's on the... way.
来るよ
Gugu...
グーグー 無理しないで
You don't have to do this.
Th-The flower...
（グーグー）は… 花…
え？
あ…
くぅ… ふんっ
うわっ
I'll... buy you a new one tomorrow.
（グーグー）あ… 明日
また買ってあげるよ
D-Don't worry.
だ… 大丈夫…
No, Gugu.
ううん グーグー
Let's go pick some together.
一緒に摘みに行きましょう
（衝撃音）
I know just one place
where those flowers grow.
私 この花が咲いてる場所
１つだけ知ってるの
You do, too.
あなたも知ってるでしょ？
（グーグー）うん
Of course.
もち… ろん…
W-We'll go for sure.
ぜ… 絶対 行こう
Rean...
（グーグー）リーン
I love you.
君が好きだ
ぐはっ
（フシ）うっ！
（酒を吐く音）
（ノッカーのうなり声）
（ノッカーの足音）
（フシ）うあっ… ぐ…
はあっ！
No...
ウソだ… ウソだ！
No!
Gugu isn't dead!
グーグーは死んでない！
He's not dead!
死んでない… 死んでない！
死んでない！　死んでない！
He's not dead!
プハッ
ぐっ…
It escaped.
（観察者）逃げた
It's traveling east.
西へ移動している 追いなさい
Go after it.
Move the rubble!
（男性）石をどかすんだ！
Hey! Get more people!
（男性）
おい もっと人を呼んでこい
Yes, sir.
（男性）はい！
Are you sure?
（観察者）いいのか？
It escaped with a part of you.
あの逃げた核の中には
お前の一部がある
（男性）そっとだ そっと…
（２人）ああ…
（駆け寄る足音）
（シン）ハァハァハァ…
ああっ
く…
（男性）よし
Hm?
（シン）ん？
Are you awake?
起きたか
Nii-chan? What are you doing?
（グーグー）
兄ちゃん！　何やってるの？
Can't you see?
見りゃ分かるだろ
お前を運んでんだよ
I'm carrying you.
Hey! Welcome home, Gugu.
（酒爺）
おーい おかえり グーグー
It looks like you're all better.
体は もういいようだな
（ピオラン）おお！
All your injuries are gone.
You're as good as new!
ケガというケガ 全部治って
きれいになっとる！
（グーグー）え？
You're right.
本当だ！
You're wonderful, Gugu!
すてきよ グーグー！
Rean.
リーン
Now, you have to keep your promise.
さあ！　私との約束 守ってね
We're going flower-picking together.
これから一緒に花を摘みに行くの
Okay.
うん！
Huh?
あれ？
What happened to the enemy?
敵は どうなったの？
Did we take down that big thing?
あのデカいヤツ 倒したの？
Where's Fushi?
フシは？　あいつはどこ？
Where is he?
（グーグー）ああ… そうか…
I see.
Are you really leaving, Fushi?
（酒爺）
本当に出ていくのか フシ？
Yeah.
（フシ）うん
You don't have to be in such a hurry.
何も そこまで急がんでも…
The enemy will come to me.
敵はオレの所へ来る
I don't want anyone else to die because of me.
オレのせいで
だれかが死ぬのは もうイヤだ
（酒爺）うむ…
Shin says he'll help from now on.
シンが あとのこと
助けてくれるって
So...
だから…
オレがいなくなっても大丈夫
You'll be fine without me.
Shin-san, it's time.
（使用人）シンさん 時間です
Right.
おう
（使用人）じゃあ 頼むね
You bought so many steamed buns.
（使用人）
こんなに まんじゅうを買って
Where are you taking them?
どこへ行かれるんですか？
To my kid brother.
（シン）弟の所だ
You mean your little brother's
going to eat all that?
（使用人）まさか…
それ全部 弟さんが？
Yeah. He sure is.
ああ 食べるぞ
He's bigger than I am.
俺よりデカいんだ あいつ
あ…
ハッ
Gugu...
グーグー！
Rean-sama!
（侍女）え… リーン様？
（リーンの荒い息）
I had a dream.
（グーグー）俺 夢を見てたんだ
It was pure happiness.
幸せ そのもの
理想そのものだった
Everything you could ever want.
But something was missing.
でも何か足りなかった
I realized that was my true self.
気づいたんだ
それは本当の自分だ
Fushi, I don't have any regrets, all right?
フシ 俺 全然
後悔なんかしてないからな
あ！
What's wrong, Fushi?
（グーグー）どうした フシ？
Oh, no...
どうしよう この姿じゃ…
I can't be in this form.
Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, no...
どうしよう どうしよう
どうしよう どうしよう…
Gugu!
グーグー！
Thank goodness. You're all right.
よかった… 無事だったのね！
Gugu, I love you.
グーグー 大好き！
Why am I me?
（フシ）
なんでオレはオレなんだろう…
ん？　大丈夫 グーグー？
Are you all right, Gugu?
Y-Yeah, I'm fine.
（フシ）うん 大丈夫
Oh, yeah! Where's Fushi-san?
そうだ フシさんは？
いるんでしょ？
He's here, isn't he?
Fushi died.
（フシ）フシは… 死んだよ
え？
No...
ウソよ… そんなはず…
That can't be...
See? This is his grave.
（フシ）ほら これが お墓だよ
He was such a brave, wonderful person.
彼は とても… 勇敢で…
すてきな人だったわ
（リーンの泣き声）
Now, Gugu, we'll take care of her.
さあ グーグー
あとは わしらに任せて
Don't you have to be going?
そろそろ
行かなきゃならんのだろう？
O-Oh... Yeah.
（フシ）あ… ああ うん
You're right.
そうだった
What?
Where are you going?
何？　どこへ行くの？
Um...
（フシ）えっと… あっ 買い物だよ
Shopping.
I'll come with you.
私も行く！　手伝うわ
I'll help.
He can go by himself.
１人で大丈夫じゃ
See you later, Rean.
リーン またあとでな
O-Okay.
（リーン）じゃ… じゃあ
あなたが帰ってきたら…
Let's go flower-picking when you get back.
一緒に花を摘みましょう
Where we promised we would.
約束した あの場所で！
I'll be there waiting.
私 先に行って待ってるわ
Y-Yeah.
（フシ）う… うん
Yay!
やった！　ずっと待ってる！
I'll see you there.
Oh, right.
あっ そうだ
There's something I need
to give back to you.
あなたに返さないといけない物が
あったんだ
Here.
はい これ…
お兄さんから預かってたの
Your brother left it with me.
You remember, don't you?
覚えてるでしょ？
Oh...
（フシ）ああ…
You hold on to it, Rean.
リーンが持ってて
そのほうがグ…
It'll help you remember Gu—
It'll help you remember me.
オレのこと
思い出してくれるでしょ？
Okay. I appreciate it.
うん！　うれしい ありがとう
Thank you.
Now, Gugu, take this.
（酒爺）さあ グーグー
これを持っていけ
It's not much, but it's some food and money.
少ないがメシとカネじゃ
Take care.
気をつけてな
Thanks.
（フシ）ありがとう
Rean!
（リーンの父）
リーン！
Rean! We've been looking for you everywhere.
リーン
ずいぶん捜したぞ
Honestly...
まったく…
You finally wake up, and here
you are, so late at night.
やっと目覚めたと
思ったら
こんな所に
夜遅くまで…
You're going to get sick.
体に障るじゃないか
Now, let's go home.
さあ 帰ろう
Dad, I...
（リーン）パパ 私ね…
I'm not going to get married.
私 結婚やめる
I'm in love with someone.
好きな人ができたの
You're in love?
（父）好きな人？
With whom? Let me meet him right away.
誰だ？
すぐに私に会わせなさい
The thing is...
（リーン）それがね…
He's no longer here.
もう ここにはいないの
ん？
I'm sure he's with him.
きっと…
彼と一緒にいるんだわ
Preview
Lives and memories, helplessly taken
from him by a powerful force.
（観察者）大きな力の前に
なす術(すべ)なく奪われた命と記憶
During Fushi's time of agony and distress,
one person comes to his aid.
悩みもがくフシに
寄り添う者がいた
Determined, they set out
and are met by new people.
決意を胸に旅立つフシたちに
新たな出会いが待ち受ける
Aspiring to Go Higher